



Contact Details

oshojoseph2@gmail.com

2349134248820

• Links •



GITHUB



**PORTFOLIO** 



LINKEDIN

Programming Skills

HTML

CSS

**JAVASCRIPT** 

REACT

**REACT NATIVE** 

NODE JS / EXPRESS

**MONGODB** 

**POSTGRESL** 

AWS

**DYNAMODB** 

**MARIADB** 

**BOOSTSTRAP** 

**JQUERY** 

**KUBERNETES** 

DOCKER

Hard Skills

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP

ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR

ADOBE XD

**FIGMA** 

Soft Skills

**LEADERSHIP** 

COMMUNICATION

CRITICAL THINKING

# •

#### **PROFILE**

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with 3+ years' experience in application layers, presentation layers, and databases. Certified in both Front/End and Back/End technologies. An astute learner seeking to further improve in further Web skills and framework technologies as future stack development comes into relevance.

# **DO**D

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER at REMEDY PORTAL

#### June 2022 - Present

Lead the frontend development team consisting of 3 team members in :

- Developing web based responsive applications such as the Remedy Portal rebranded cv landing page, The Hair-market ecommerce website using React framework.
- Development of Frontend Mobile Native App Features for the remedy app some of which include push notifications, Universal app deep linking, biometric authentication and google authentication for both Android and IOS Platform release.
- Testing of beta app releases features on both android and IOS platform.
   Publishing of compiled final build release version of application to Google Play store for android platform and app store for IOS Platform.
- Creating and submitting PR for features implemented in the applications.
   Integration of backend to frontend API's for consumption and rendering of data for usage on the web browser.
- Developing a backup full stack web application of the remedy cv page to collect customers information, process payment, submit information, store in database and mail to customer service department for processing while server was down.

## FULL STACK DEVELOPER at TECHNOKRAFT

#### June 2021 - June 2022

- Developed full-stack functional web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Spearheaded and liaised with back-end developers, front-end developers, designers, quality
  assurance testers, and CTO as needed for the creation of responsive and functional web
  applications.
- Setup and Deployment of web application on web server hosting platforms and on cloud platforms such as heroku and AWS.
- Managed time-sensitive updates to web applications, including content changes and database upgrades.

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER at Digibrand

#### January 2020 - June 2021

- Maximized applications' efficiency, data quality, scope, operability, and flexibility.
- Managed and updated MongoDB database structure as necessary and for use in user authentication for web applications
- Developed app integration with REST APIs for google maps, social media logins, payment processing gateways, and other services.
- Development of a real time chat web application using socket io as transport connection and node as backend.
- Built an ecommerce web app to sell products online. Increased company sales by 58%.

# PROBLEM SOLVING TEAM BUILDING.

- Built a bitcoin/crypto sales and conversion to fiat currency website with data fetched from coin gecko API in real time and email notifications
- Development of hospital management system for medical staff and patient data storage for a local private hospital. Increased patient satisfaction scores by 30%
- Development of web application with NFT cards for decentralized finance crypto trading
  platform which its details are stored on a cloud database and can be dynamically
  changed and managed by the authorized administrative role assigned using React
  framework and node technology.
- Development and integration of web3 wallet connect authentication for Ethereum Blockchain transactions.
- Built a web scraper bot with node/express backend and react frontend to login and fetch MT4 trading signals for client use on frontend.

# 

# EDUCATION.

## **Higher National Diploma**

Moshood Abiola Polytechnic, Abeokuta

Graduation: 2020

**Relevant Coursework:** Operating Systems Architecture, C# Programming, Usability in Technologies and Software Design, Relational Database Design & SQL, Computer Engineering



# Certifications

Front-End Web Development with React

December 2021 to Present

A Certification on Coursera from the University of Science and Technology Hong Kong for successful completion on React Course.

## UDACITY Cloud Development Nanodegree

November 2022 to Present

Nanodegree certification awarded for completion of cloud development course with experience in monolith, micro service and serverless app